<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authors on Paisajes resilientes ante incendios forestales</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/</link><description>Recent content in Authors on Paisajes resilientes ante incendios forestales</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href="authors/carojeda/"> Carolina G. Ojeda &lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Carolina G. Ojeda</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/carojeda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/carojeda/</guid><description>Magíster en Desarrollo Regional y Medio Ambiente de la Universidad de Valparaíso y graduada como profesora de Historia y Geografía de la Universidad de Concepción. Actualmente es estudiante del Programa Doctorado en Arquitectura y Estudios Urbanos, Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile. También es Profesora part time del Departamento de Historia y Geografía, Facultad de Comunicación, Historia y Cs. Sociales, Universidad Católica de la Santísima Concepción.</description></item><item><title>Jossef Guajardo</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/jguajardo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/jguajardo/</guid><description>Jossef is an Illustrator from Chile with a Degree in Physics. He is currently a Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree Student at the Universidad de Concepción (UdeC) and he specializes on Biophysics, in particular, active soft matter applied to collective cell migration in embryo development. As an artist, he draws comics and posters, and he also tries to mix arts and science.</description></item><item><title>Karen Ojeda Leal</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/kojeda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/kojeda/</guid><description>She has translated geography-related papers for Facultad de Arquitectura, Urbanismo y Geografía, UdeC. She edited a class handbook on sustainability for Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile and is currently translating an article about it.</description></item><item><title>Roberto E. Navarro</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/rnavarro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/es/authors/rnavarro/</guid><description>Roberto is Assistant Professor in the Physics Department of the Faculty of Physical and Mathematical Sciences of the Universidad de Concepción. He joined the institution through the program of Insertion of Advanced Human Capital in the Academy (PAI) of CONICyT.
He specializes in Space Plasma Physics, in particular, he researches on the basic processes that govern the heating and energization of plasmas in the Universe as well as their importance in different turbulent regimes in space physics, astrophysical and laboratory plasmas.</description></item></channel></rss>