<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authors on Fire Resilient Landscapes</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/</link><description>Recent content in Authors on Fire Resilient Landscapes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href="authors/carojeda/"> Carolina G. Ojeda &lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Carolina G. Ojeda</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/carojeda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/carojeda/</guid><description>Carolina is a History and Geography teacher, graduated from the Universidad de Concepción, and studied a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Regional and Environmental Development at the Universidad de Valparaíso (Chile). She is currently a student of the Doctoral Program in Architecture and Urban Studies from Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile. She is also a part time professor at the Department of History and Geography, Faculty of Communication, History and Social Sciences, Universidad Católica de la Santísima Concepción.</description></item><item><title>Jossef Guajardo</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/jguajardo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/jguajardo/</guid><description>Selfintroduction Carolina is a History and Geography teacher, graduated from the Universidad de Concepción, and studied a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Regional and Environmental Development at the Universidad de Valparaíso (Chile). She is currently a student of the Doctoral Program in Architecture and Urban Studies from Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile. She is also a part time professor at the Department of History and Geography, Faculty of Communication, History and Social Sciences, Universidad Católica de la Santísima Concepción.</description></item><item><title>Karen Ojeda Leal</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/kojeda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/kojeda/</guid><description>She has translated geography-related papers for Facultad de Arquitectura, Urbanismo y Geografía, UdeC. She edited a class handbook on sustainability for Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile and is currently translating an article about it.</description></item><item><title>Roberto E. Navarro</title><link>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/rnavarro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fire-resilient-landscapes.github.io/authors/rnavarro/</guid><description>Roberto is Assistant Professor in the Physics Department of the Faculty of Physical and Mathematical Sciences of the Universidad de Concepción. He joined the institution through the program of Insertion of Advanced Human Capital in the Academy (PAI) of CONICyT.
He specializes in Space Plasma Physics, in particular, he researches on the basic processes that govern the heating and energization of plasmas in the Universe as well as their importance in different turbulent regimes in space physics, astrophysical and laboratory plasmas.</description></item></channel></rss>